Harriet Whitney Frishmuth Papers
Harriet Whitney Frishmuth Papers
1825-2002
Frishmuth, Harriet Whitney, 1880-1980
32.0 linear ft.
Papers of the American sculptor, including original artwork and reproductions, correspondence and memorabilia as well as some family history of both Frishmuth and her longtime companion Ruth Talcott.
148992
Biographical History
Harriet W. Frishmuth (1880-1980) was an American sculptor. Born in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, on September 17, 1880, she studied art in Paris under Rodin and Injalbert, in Berlin under Euchteitz and at the Art Students' League under Borglum and McNeil, where she was awarded the St. Gaudens first prize. Her work has been exhibited at the National Academy of Design, the Academy of Fine Arts in Philadelphia, the Salon in Paris, the San Francisco Exposition (1939-1940) and the National Association of Women Painters and Sculptors.
Frishmuth received several awards from the National Academy of Design, a prize from the Grand Central Art Galleries, an honorable mention from the San Francisco Exposition and the Joan of Arc Silver Medal from the National Association of Women Painters and Sculptors.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Harriet Whitney Frishmuth Papers consists of artwork originals and reproductions, audiovisual material, biographical material, correspondence subject files, financial and legal material, memorabilia and writings.
Artwork originals includes plaster and bronze models of her sculpture as well as sketches and paintings.
Artwork reproductions consists of a fairly complete photographic record of Ms. Frishmuth's work.
Audiovisual material includes audiotapes and a transcript of reminiscences compiled for an article in The Courier (1971) and amateur films of vacation trips.
Biographical material is some short biographical sketches and obituaries.
Correspondence-subject files include both personal and business correspondence as well as information on various galleries and organizations with which Ms. Frishmuth was associated.
Financial and legal material includes records of sales and foundry orders as well as copyright certificates and tax returns.
Memorabilia includes a caricature of Harriet Frishmuth by Matias Santoyo, awards and certficates, catalogs of shows and galleries, clipppings, photographs, postcards from vacations, printed material scrapbooks of family history and Ms. Frishmuth's sculpture and miscellaneous souvenirs.
Writings contains two vacation diaries and an essay.
Arrangement of the Collection
The Harriet Whitney Frishmuth Papers are arranged by category of material and alphabetically within each category.
Related Material
has the papers of more than 60 sculptors, including Anna Hyatt Huntington, James Earle Fraser and his wife Laura Gardin Fraser, and Brenda Putnam. Please see for a complete listing.
Separated Material
A few books have been removed from the collection and transferred to Rare Books for separate cataloging.
Subject and Genre Headings
Art -- Sculptors; Frishmuth, Harriet Whitney, 1880-1980.; Alpert, Sidney A.; Aronson, Charles N., 1913-; Barté, Leon.; Borglum, Gutzon, 1867-1941.; Brownell, Herbert, 1904-1996.; Chrysler, Walter P. (Walter Percy), 1909-1988.; Deltiel, Desha.; Huntington, Anna Hyatt, 1876-1973.; Putnam, Brenda, 1890-1975.; Watson, Thomas J., 1914-1993.; Wilson, Edith Bolling Galt, 1872-1961.; Allied Architects of Los Angeles.; American National Red Cross.; Brookgreen Gardens.; The Gorham Company; Grand Central Art Galleries.; National Academy of Design (U.S.); National Sculpture Society (U.S.); New York World's Fair (1939-1940: New York, N.Y.); Roman Bronze Works; Art, American -- 20th century.; Sculptors -- United States.; Sculpture, American -- 20th century.; Women artists -- United States.; Women sculptors -- United States.; 8mm (photographic film size); 16mm (photographic film size); Awards.; Bank statements.; Bas-reliefs (sculpture); Bills of sale.; Blueprints (reprographic copies); Clippings (information artifacts); Commemorative sculpture.; Copper engravings (printing process); Correspondence.; Daguerreotypes (photographs); Diaries.; Glass plate negatives.; Models (representations); Oil paintings (visual works); Photographs.; Receipts (financial records); Scrapbooks.; Sculpture (visual works); Sketches.; Watercolors (paintings); Sound recordings.; Artists.; Sculptors.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Majority of collection gift of Harriet Frishmuth, 1967-1980.
Some memorabilia gift of Ruth Talcott, 1985.
"Dorothea" bronze relief and plaster relief, and plaster bust of infant gift of Bettina Huffman, 2010.
Inventory
- Artwork originals
  - Bas relief portrait plaster cast, undated (Oversize 3)
  - Child bust plaster, undated (Oversize 2)
  - Dancing Fawn bronze, undated (Oversize 2)
  - Desha bust plaster, 1921 (Oversize 2)
  - Engraving original for copper plate, undated (Oversize 9)
  - Etchings, prints and copper plates, undated (Box 1)
  - Figure of woman plaster, undated (Oversize 1)
  - Frishmuth, Dorothea portrait relief, undated; 2 plaster, 1 bronze (Oversize 3)
  - Frishmuth Louise B. portrait relief bronze, undated (Box 1)
  - Garden Club of America medal bronze, undated (Box 1)
  - Jack portrait relief bronze, undated (Box 1)
  - Jack portrait relief wax casting, undated (Oversize 3)
  - Joy of the Waters template of base, undated (Box 1)
  - Maison Beaufait Abbott Children’s Home medal bronze, undated (Box 1)
  - Morton Memorial sketches, undated (Box 1)
  - Norfolk Tribute sketches, undated (Box 1)
  - Oil painting, undated (Oversize 10)
  - Pencil sketches, 1936 (Oversize 11)
  - Playdays sketches, undated (Box 1)
  - Sketch book, undated (Box 1)
  - Sketches, miscellaneous, undated (Box 1)
  - Stanhope Memorial sketches, undated (Box 1)
  - Watercolors Lake Pleasant, undated (Oversize 10)
  - Wilcox Memorial sketches, undated (Box 1)
  - Woman’s head relief bronze, undated (Box 1)
- Artwork reproductions
  - Allegra, photographs, undated (Box 2)
  - Angel of Consolation photographs, undated (Box 2)
  - Ardmore Fountain photographs, undated (Box 2)
  - Aspiration photographs, undated (Box 2)
  - Baker, Ella K. Memorial photographs, undated (Box 2)
  - Benjamin, William E. Memorial photographs, undated (Box 2)
  - Berens, T. Passmore Memorial photographs, undated (Box 2)
  - Beyond photographs, undated (Oversize 11)
  - Boy with Urn photographs, undated (Box 2)
  - The Bubble photographs, undated (Box 2)
  - Bull Dog photographs, undated (Box 2)
  - Call of the Sea photographs, undated (Box 2)
  - Campbell Memorial photographs, undated (Box 2)
  - Caprice photographs, undated (Box 2)
  - Cathalene photographs, undated (Box 2)
  - The Christ photographs, undated (Box 2)
  - Cooper, Dorothea photographs, undated (Box 2)
  - Courtney, Frederick Memorial photographs, undated (Box 2)
  - Crest of the Wave photographs, undated (Box 2)
  - The Dancers photographs, undated (Box 2)
  - Dancing Fawn photographs, undated (Box 2)
  - Day Dreams photographs, undated (Box 2)
  - Desha – full figure photographs, undated (Box 2)
  - Desha – head portrait photographs, undated (Box 2)
  - Desha- head portrait copper engraving, undated (Box 2)
  - Diana photographs, undated (Box 2)
  - Dill Memorial The Beyond photographs, undated (Box 2)
  - Dreams photographs, undated (Box 2)
  - Dryad in Bronze photographs, undated (Oversize 11)
  - Eagle Radiator Cap photographs, undated (Box 2)
  - Extase photographs, undated (Box 2)
  - Flower Holder photographs, undated (Box 2)
  - Fokine’s Thunderbird photographs, undated (Box 2)
  - Fountains photographs, undated (Box 3)
  - The Garden Club of America photographs, undated (Box 3)
  - Gay, Janet photographs, undated (Box 3)
  - Globe Sundial photographs, undated (Box 3)
  - Goddard Memorial photographs, undated (Box 3)
  - Goddess of Happiness photographs, undated (Box 3)
  - Gorham Co. Sculpture Exhibition pieces photographs, undated (Box 3)
  - Grand Central Art Gallery photographs, undated (Box 3)
  - Hogan, Frank J. photographs, undated (Box 3)
  - Humoresque photographs, undated (Box 3)
  - The Hunt photographs, undated (Box 3)
  - Joy of the Waters photographs, undated (Box 3)
  - Knickerbocker, William H. photographs, undated (Box 3)
  - Knox, Henry D. photographs, undated (Box 3)
  - Laughing Waters photographs, undated (Box 3)
  - Laughing Waters copper, undated (Box 3)
  - Longing photographs, undated (Box 3)
  - McCullough Memorial photographs, undated (Box 3)
  - Meteor photographs, undated (Box 3)
  - Morton Memorial photographs, undated (Box 3)
  - New York Academy of Medicine Medal photographs, undated (Box 3)
  - Norfolk Tribute photographs, undated (Box 3)
  - Papillon photographs, undated (Box 3)
  - Peter Pan photographs, undated (Box 3)
  - Peter Pan copper engraving, undated (Box 3)
  - The Pioneer Mother photographs, undated (Box 3)
  - Playdays photographs, 1925 (Box 3)
  - Reflection photographs, 1930 (Box 3)
  - Reflection photographs, 1930 (Oversize 11)
  - Reflection copper engraving, undated (Box 5)
  - Reflection copper engraving, undated (Box 6)
  - Revolt photographs, undated (Box 3)
  - Rhapsody photographs, undated (Box 3)
  - Roses of Yesterday photographs, undated (Box 4)
  - Saki Sundial photographs, undated (Box 4)
  - Scherzo photographs, undated (Box 4)
  - Siren’s Call photographs, undated (Box 4)
  - Slavonic Dancer photographs, undated (Box 4)
  - Speed photographs, 1925 (Box 4)
  - Spring Voices photographs, undated (Box 4)
  - The Star photograph, undated (Oversize 10)
  - Sundials photographs, undated (Box 4)
  - Sweet Grapes photographs, undated (Box 4)
  - Sweet Grapes copper engraving, undated (Box 6)
  - The Trio fountain photographs, undated (Box 4)
  - Valentine, Lila Meade Memorial photographs, undated (Box 4)
  - The Vine photographs, undated (Box 4, Oversize 9)
  - The Vine copper engraving, undated (Box 6)
  - Wilcox Memorial photographs, undated (Box 4)
  - Wilson, Woodrow photographs, undated (Box 4)
  - Wilson, Woodrow copper, undated (Box 6)
  - Woman and Frog photographs, undated (Box 4)
  - Miscellaneous unidentified works, undated (Box 4)
  - Miscellaneous unidentified glass plate negatives, undated (Box 7)
  - Miscellaneous unidentified glass plate negatives, undated (Box 8)
  - Miscellaneous unidentified glass plate negatives, undated (Box 9)
  - Miscellaneous unidentified glass plate negatives, undated (Box 10)
  - Miscellaneous unidentified glass plate negatives, undated (Box 11)
- Audiovisual material
  - Audio tapes
    - [Gutzon] Borglum, [Karl] Bitter; Purchase Sniffen Court; First Commissions; Meeting Desha (3 of 12), 1964; frishmuth_hw_003; Series of tape recordings made by Miss Frishmuth, accompanied by The Courier 9.1 (1971) article: "Harriet Whitney Frishmuth, American Sculptor".; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 14)
    - [Ruth] Talcott childhood, North Dakota State Penitentiary, frishmuth_hw_014; 1/8 inch audio cassette; running time 60:00 (Box 14)
    - [Untitled], frishmuth_hw_015; Side No. 1 and No. 2 are indicated on the cassette.; 1/8 inch audio cassette; running time 60:00 (Box 14)
    - Army tape, frishmuth_hw_013; Most likely the content of the audio recording refers to Ruth Talcott's army life.; 1/8 inch audio cassette; running time 90:00 (Box 14)
    - Aspiration; Beyond; Garden Club Medal (11 of 12), 1964; frishmuth_hw_011; Series of tape recordings made by Miss Frishmuth, accompanied by The Courier 9.1 (1971) article: "Harriet Whitney Frishmuth, American Sculptor". Additional note on the tape box reads: "Portrait and Memories. Relief done direct in metal etchings".; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 14)
    - Childhood and Education (1 of 12), 1964; frishmuth_hw_001; Series of tape recordings made by Miss Frishmuth, accompanied by The Courier 9.1 (1971) article: "Harriet Whitney Frishmuth, American Sculptor".; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 14)
    - Desha; Philadelphia; Moved to New York (4 of 12), 1964; frishmuth_hw_004; Series of tape recordings made by Miss Frishmuth, accompanied by The Courier 9.1 (1971) article: "Harriet Whitney Frishmuth, American Sculptor".; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 14)
    - Education; Early Studies; Rodin Class (2 of 12), 1964; frishmuth_hw_002; Series of tape recordings made by Miss Frishmuth, accompanied by The Courier 9.1 (1971) article: "Harriet Whitney Frishmuth, American Sculptor".; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 14)
    - Large Bronzes; Notes on Works; Vine (6 of 12), 1964; frishmuth_hw_006; Series of tape recordings made by Miss Frishmuth, accompanied by The Courier 9.1 (1971) article: "Harriet Whitney Frishmuth, American Sculptor". Additional note on the tape box reads: "Large Bronzes".; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 14)
    - New York; [Reminiscences]; Silver Mine; Syracuse (5 of 12), 1964; frishmuth_hw_005; Series of tape recordings made by Miss Frishmuth, accompanied by The Courier 9.1 (1971) article: "Harriet Whitney Frishmuth, American Sculptor".; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 14)
    - Papillon to Peter Pan to Poo-Poo (8 of 12), 1964; frishmuth_hw_008; Series of tape recordings made by Miss Frishmuth, accompanied by The Courier 9.1 (1971) article: "Harriet Whitney Frishmuth, American Sculptor". Additional note on the tape box reads: "Book marked".; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 14)
    - Plaster Casts shipped Syracuse (12 of 12), 12-14-1964; frishmuth_hw_012; Series of tape recordings made by Miss Frishmuth, accompanied by The Courier 9.1 (1971) article: "Harriet Whitney Frishmuth, American Sculptor".; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 14)
    - Portraits and Memorials (9 of 12), 1964; frishmuth_hw_009; Series of tape recordings made by Miss Frishmuth, accompanied by The Courier 9.1 (1971) article: "Harriet Whitney Frishmuth, American Sculptor".; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 14)
    - Portraits and Memorials; President Wilson; The Christ (10 of 12), 1964; frishmuth_hw_010; Series of tape recordings made by Miss Frishmuth, accompanied by The Courier 9.1 (1971) article: "Harriet Whitney Frishmuth, American Sculptor".; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 14)
    - Vine; Call of Sea; Crest of Wave; Play Days; Goddess of Happiness; Papillon (7 of 12), 1964; frishmuth_hw_007; Series of tape recordings made by Miss Frishmuth, accompanied by The Courier 9.1 (1971) article: "Harriet Whitney Frishmuth, American Sculptor". Additional note on the tape box reads: "Large Bronzes".; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 14)
  - Transcript of tapes, 2002 (Box 14)
  - Computer media
    - Master CD (1 of 2), frishmuth_hw_016; unknown content; CD (Box 14)
    - Master CD (2 of 2), frishmuth_hw_017; unknown content; CD (Box 14)
  - Films
    - 3 French destroyers in Stockholm Harbor; Helsinki Rug washing, Mannerheim Memorial [?] (7 of 13), frishmuth_hw_025; Part of series of amateur films of Miss Frishmuth's trip around Europe. Scenes from trips in Stockholm, Sweden and Helsinki, Finland, also depicts Alexander II (Romanov) monument on the Senate Square in Helsinki, other statues and a graveyard. Accompanied by a piece of a Kodakchrome box with handwritten labels on it.; Film: 8mm; running time 04:00 ([barcoded item])
    - Åndalsnes to Meråker via Geirangerfjord (3 of 13), frishmuth_hw_021; Part of series of amateur films of Miss Frishmuth's trip around Europe. Scenes from trips in Norway. Accompanied by a piece of a Kodakchrome box with handwritten labels on it, some illegible, or faded text.; Film: 8mm; running time 04:00 ([barcoded item])
    - Curacao; Jamaica, frishmuth_hw_033; An amateur film of Miss Frishmuth's trips to Curacao and Jamaica. Depicts street views, harbors, markets, landscape, Miss Frishmuth in various scenes, sailors, boats.; Film: 8mm; running time 04:00 ([barcoded item])
    - Delft Holland: Market; Edam cheese 80K; Poultry plant; Dum hang hare [?]; Bagpipers; Dasein - Tumth [?]; Luncheon train; Hilversum (12 of 13), frishmuth_hw_030; Part of series of amateur films of Miss Frishmuth's trip around Europe. Depicts scenes from Netherlands cities, Royal Palace, buildings, landscape. Illegible text on the label. Accompanied by a piece of a Kodakchrome box with handwritten labels on it.; Film: 8mm; running time 04:00 ([barcoded item])
    - Denmark: Elsinor [sic]; Fredensborg; Countryside (5 of 13), frishmuth_hw_023; Part of series of amateur films of Miss Frishmuth's trip around Europe. Scenes from trips in Denmark, Kronborg castle, Fredensborg Palace, buildings. Accompanied by a piece of a Kodakchrome box with handwritten labels on it.; Film: 8mm; running time 04:00 ([barcoded item])
    - Denmark: Island of Bornholm; Østerlars round church; Iced hjecu [?] smoked herring (6 of 13), frishmuth_hw_024; Part of series of amateur films of Miss Frishmuth's trip around Europe. Scenes from trips in Denmark, depicting windmills, the Little Mermaid statue, street market, clay crafting, buildings architecture. Accompanied by a piece of a Kodakchrome box with handwritten labels on it.; Film: 8mm; running time 04:00 ([barcoded item])
    - Hamburg City; Residential; Harbor and Piers; leaving Hamburg (11 of 13), frishmuth_hw_029; Part of series of amateur films of Miss Frishmuth's trip around Europe. Depicts scenes from Hamburg, Germany, monuments, buildings, city streets. Accompanied by a piece of a Kodakchrome box with handwritten labels on it.; Film: 8mm; running time 04:00 ([barcoded item])
    - Harriet W. Frishmuth, N. A. (1935), 1935; 1936; frishmuth_hw_018; Film reel, depicting scenes of Miss Frishmuth in front of various sculptures; Miss Frishmuth knitting, accompanied by her dog; Miss Frishmuth looking at a book; Miss Frishmuth writing on her desk. The film is accompanied by an old label and a typed note. The note reads: "This movie was taken in 1936 in Miss Frishmuth's studio in Sniffen Court in New York City".; Film: 16mm ([barcoded item])
    - Ireland: Killarney; Halse Country [?]; Exit from Glasgow [?] (13 of 13), frishmuth_hw_031; Part of series of amateur films of Miss Frishmuth's trip around Europe. Depicts scenes from Ireland, England and Scotland trips, pigs on a street, various carriages, horse riding demonstrations, trip on a boat. Illegible text on the label. Accompanied by a piece of a Kodakchrome box with handwritten labels on it.; Film: 8mm; running time 04:00 ([barcoded item])
    - Leningrad (8 of 13), frishmuth_hw_026; Part of series of amateur films of Miss Frishmuth's trip around Europe. Depicts scenes from Leningrad, Russia, city architecture, St. Isaac's Cathedral, Hermitage Museum, General Staff Building. Accompanied by a piece of a Kodakchrome box with handwritten labels on it.; Film: 8mm; running time 04:00 ([barcoded item])
    - Leningrad of Pier; Kiev Council House [?]; Lock -[?] being locked in (10 of 13), frishmuth_hw_028; Part of series of amateur films of Miss Frishmuth's trip around Europe. Depicts scenes from Leningrad, harbors, sailing ships, helicopter, pier. The label has illegible notes. Accompanied by a piece of a Kodakchrome box with handwritten labels on it.; Film: 8mm; running time 04:00 ([barcoded item])
    - Leningrad; Pushkin; Valentine (9 of 13), frishmuth_hw_027; Part of series of amateur films of Miss Frishmuth's trip around Europe. Depicts scenes from Leningrad, Pushkin,city architecture, outdoor stadium. Accompanied by a piece of a Kodakchrome box with handwritten labels on it.; Film: 8mm; running time 04:00 ([barcoded item])
    - Lippazaneur [sic] Horses, May 28, 1964; frishmuth_hw_032; An amateur film of a Lipizzans demonstration, Spanish Riding School in a closed arena. Accompanied by a piece of a Kodakchrome box with handwritten labels on it.; Film: 8mm; running time 04:00 ([barcoded item])
    - Man [diving], frishmuth_hw_034; An amateur film depicting a man diving from a boat, street views, people working on a field, harbors. (Might be an additional film related to the trip to Curacao and Jamaica).; Film: 8mm; running time 04:00 ([barcoded item])
    - Midnight Scene; Lofoten Islands; Svartisen glacier; Train trip Rondalsbekken [?] (2 of 13), frishmuth_hw_020; Part of series of amateur films of Miss Frishmuth's trip around Europe. Scenes from trips on a boat or with a train in Norway. Accompanied by a piece of a Kodakchrome box with handwritten labels on it.; Film: 8mm; running time 04:00 ([barcoded item])
    - NYC - Silvermine; Reykjavik Harbor, Iceland; Hammerfest [Norway]; Scenery to North Cape [Norway]; Bird nest; Birds nesting (1 of 13), frishmuth_hw_019; Part of series of amateur films of Miss Frishmuth's trip around Europe. Accompanied by a piece of a Kodakchrome box with handwritten labels on it.; Film: 8mm; running time 04:00 ([barcoded item])
    - Oslo Harbor; Stockholm Harbor (4 of 13), frishmuth_hw_022; Part of series of amateur films of Miss Frishmuth's trip around Europe. Scenes from trips around Norway and Sweden. Accompanied by a piece of a Kodakchrome box with handwritten labels on it.; Film: 8mm; running time 04:00 ([barcoded item])
    - [Untitled], frishmuth_hw_035; An amateur film depicting a shore view, landscape, boats, buildings, Miss Frishmuth by a bird house with a dog.; Film: 8mm; running time 04:00 ([barcoded item])
- Biographical material
  - Brief biography with descriptions of early sculpture, undated (Box 12)
  - National Cyclopedia of Biography, 1927 (Box 12)
  - Obituaries, 1980 (Box 12)
- Correspondence-subject files
  - General correspondence A-N, 1919-1980; 12 folders (Box 12)
  - General correspondence O-Z, illegible or incomplete name, 1919-1980; 8 folders (Box 13)
  - Abbate, Paolo S., 1928; 1931 (Box 13)
  - Allentown Art Museum, 1972 (Box 13)
  - The Allied Architects Association of Los Angeles, 1923-1924 (Box 13)
  - Alpert, Sidney, 1973-1979 (Box 13)
  - The American Institute of Steel Construction, Inc., 1929 (Box 13)
  - American Liberty League, 1935 (Box 13)
  - American Numismatic Association, 1975-1979 (Box 13)
  - American Red Cross, 1945 (Box 13)
  - Anderson, Geneste Marie, 1965-1972 (Box 13)
  - Anderson, Geneste Marie, 1973-1979 (Box 15)
  - Antiques, 1974-1978 (Box 15)
  - The Architectural League of New York, 1934 (Box 15)
  - Aristos: The Journal of Esthetics, 1983-1984 (Box 15)
  - Aronson, Charles N., 1958-1972; 3 folders (Box 15)
  - Art Alliance of America, 1929 (Box 15)
  - Art in Public Places in the United States, 1972-1974 (Box 15)
  - Art Workers’ Club for Women, 1929-1931 (Box 15)
  - Baldrey, Haynsworth, 1933 (Box 15)
  - The Webb C. Ball Company, 1947-1953 (Box 15)
  - Barté, Leon, 1928 (Box 15)
  - Beech-Nut Packing Company Canajoharie, New York, 1930-1931 (Box 15)
  - Bendan Art Galleries Baltimore, Maryland, 1947-1959 (Box 15)
  - Berens, Bernard, 1929 (Box 16)
  - Berry-Hill Galleries, 1984 (Box 16)
  - Black, Starr and Gorham, Inc., 1945-1955 (Box 16)
  - Blackstone- Shelburne, 1967 (Box 16)
  - Blodgett, Glen Walton, 1929 (Box 16)
  - Borglum, Gutzon, 1907; 1910,; undated (Box 16)
  - Boyce, R. C., 1970; 1974-1975 (Box 16)
  - The F.H. Bressler Company Milwaukee, Wisconsin, 1947-1954 (Box 16)
  - Brookgreen Gardens, 1936-1939; 1942,; 1966,; 1972 (Box 16)
  - Brooklyn Botanic Garden, 1936; 1938,; 1976 (Box 16)
  - Brown, Harold X., 1977 (Box 16)
  - Browne, George Elmer, 1929 (Box 16)
  - Brownell, Herbert, 1934 (Box 16)
  - W. S. Budworth & Son, 1949; 1960,; 1969,; 1970 (Box 16)
  - The Buffalo Fine Arts Academy Buffalo, New York, 1924 (Box 16)
  - Bush, Martin H., 1971 (Box 16)
  - Cahn, Joshua Binion, 1949-1950 (Box 16)
  - Caldwell, Henry Bryan, 1965-1973 (Box 16)
  - J. E. Caldwell and Company, 1947-1955 (Box 16)
  - Chamberlain, Dorothy J., 1967-1968 (Box 16)
  - Chekow, Arnold, 1974 (Box 16)
  - Chicago World’s Fair, 1933 (Box 16)
  - Christie, Manson & Woods International, Inc., 1981 (Box 16)